RICARDO CABALLERO

GAME DESIGNER

Madrid, Spain

(+34) 667-265-008

rcaballero.pascual@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Passionate game designer with 5+ years of experience developing video games with a strong narrative component. I have worked on original projects or based on third party IPs. Eager to explore new horizons helping to design and deliver new products.

EDUCATION

University of Technology, Arts and Design (U-TAD)

Official Bachelor Degree in Game Design

2016 - 2020

KEY SKILLS

- Game design
- Level design
- Narrative design
- Research
- Documentation

SOFTWARE

- Unity
- Unreal Engine
- C# & Blueprints
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Premiere Pro
- Microsoft Office
- SourceTree

EXPERIENCE

February, 2023 – Current

Game Designer • AHEARTFULOFGAMES, Spain

- Designed and developed cutscenes for 'Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Mutants Unleashed' (2024).
- Designed and developed cutscenes for 'Ironskins' (to be launched).
- Worked on the redesign and balancing of several mechanichs for 'Ironskins' (to be launched).

October, 2020 - January, 2023

Game Designer • Drakhar Studio, Spain

- Designed and built multiple levels giving flow and pacing special consideration for 'PAW Patrol The Movie: Adventure City Calls' (2021), 'Hotel Transylvania: Scary-Tale Adventures' (2022) and 'Cry Babies Magic Tears: The Great Game' (2023),
- Worked with existing systems to implement complex events and behaviours.
- Partnered with other team members to improve the workflow and test new ideas.
- Redesigned the narrative branching system and gameplay proposal for 'One Night', a VR horror experience.

September, 2019 – September, 2020

Narrative Designer • Null Reference Studio, Spain

- Designed all the narrative of 'Burn Me Twice' (2020), and wrote almost all the texts within the game, including the script.
- Created all characters and designed their respective rutines in 'Burn Me Twice' (2020).
- 'Burn Me Twice' (2020) has been awarded as the best game made by students in three major international game festivals: Gamelab 2020, Fun&Serious 2020 and Game Development World Championship 2020.

September, 2016 – June, 2018

Game Designer • Black Sorrows Team

- Collaborated with other students to design 'Black Sorrows', a horror experience in virtual reality
- Organized the game documentation, and helped to design the narrative
- 'Black Sorrows' was exhibited in the National Archaeological Museum (Spain), in ESVR (Spain) and in Madrid Gaming Experience 2018 (Spain)

LANGUAGES

English — Advanced (C1.1) Japanese — Beginner (N5) Spanish — Native speaker

INTERESTS

Reading novels and writing stories Urban legends and local folklore Tabletop role-playing games Survival Horror games

Law (currently studying for a Law Degree at the Spanish National Distance Education University)